Mss.B.P31
American Philosophical Society
- Series 1: Correspondence, 1675-1960; 27 boxes, 8.5 linear feet
  - Letter to [Coleman] Sellers, Dec. 17, 1871; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1809-1894
    Boston, A.L.S. 2p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Concerning a publication. Concerning spiritualism and refers to Huxley.
  - Letter to J[onathan] S. Miles, Jan. 16, 1872; 8x5; Sellers, George Escol
    A.L.S.with initials. 4p. Draft. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Business letter, concerning debts related to Coleman Sellers, etc.
  - Letter to Burd [Peale], Aug. 3, 1872; 7-1/2x4-3/4; Peale, Caroline, 1798-1878
    Germantown, A.L.S. 2p. (see Peale papers.) Wishes to know his feelings on her harshness to Coleman.
  - Letter to [Mary Jane Peale?], Nov. 26, 1872; 8x5; Peale, Lucinda MacMullen, d. 1885
    Washington, A.L.S.: Aung Lucy. 3p. (see Peale papers.) Concerning portraits by Charles Willson Peale and a Peale portrait of Washington.
  - Letter to [Coleman] Sellers, Feb. 8, 1873; 6x4-1/2; Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1809-1894
    Boston, A.L.S. 4p (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Concerning a recent publication of his. Photography.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Escol Sellers, Dec. 23, 1873; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Warner, Charles Dudley, 1829-1900
    Hartford, A.L.S. 2p.and end. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Regrets that the name in Gilded Age resembles his.
  - Letter to G[eorge] E[scol] Sellers, Dec. 26, 1873; 8x5; Barton, J. Hervey (Box 18)
    A.L.S. 4p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Concerning the use of his name in The Gilded Age.
  - Letter to [Charles Dudley Warner], Jan. 1, 1874; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Sellers, George Escol (Box 19)
    A.L.S. 2p. Draft. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Concerning the use of his name in Gilded Age.
  - Letter to G[eorge] Escol Sellers, Jan. 7, 1874; 8-1/2x5-1/2, 9-3/4x7-3/4; Warner, Charles Dudley, 1829-1900
    Hartford, A.L.S. 3p.and end. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Regrets the use of his name in Gilded Age. ----Copy. 1p.
  - Letter to G[eorge] Escol Sellers, Jan. 13, 1874; 8x5; Warner, Charles Dudley, 1829-1900
    Hartford, A.L.S. 2p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Is correcting the name in Gilded Age.
  - Letter to G[eorge] Escol Sellers, Jan. 15, 1874; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Warner, Charles Dudley, 1829-1900
    Hartford, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Has changed the name of the man in Gilded Age.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s D[udley] Warner, Jan. 17, 1874; 9x5-1/2; Sellers, George Escol
    Philadelphia, A.L. 2p. Draft. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Concerning the distribution and sale of Gilded Age.
  - Telegram to G[eorge] E[scol] Sellers, Philadelphia, Jan. 17, 1874; 8x5-1/2; Warner, Charles Dudley, 1829-1900
    Hartford, D. 1p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Will be in New York Wednesday.
  - Telegram to G[eorge] E[scol] Sellers, Philadelphia, Jan. 19, 1874; 7-3/4x5-1/4; Warner, Charles Dudley, 1829-1900
    Hartford, D. 1p.and add.,end. (See Peale-Sellers papers.) Suggests he act with American publishing company, concerning the use of his name in Gilded Age.
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Feb. 27, 1874; Kelly, William D.
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, April 29, 1874; 8x5; Hilgard, J. E. (Julius Erasmus), 1825-1891
    Washington, A.L.S.2p. He may use his arguments, but not quote them, on the metric system.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] E[scol] Sellers, March 8, 1875; 10x8; Grammer, G. J.
    Evansville, Ind., A.L.S. 1p.and end. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Concerning the Gilded Age and the use of his name in it.
  - Letter to [George Escol Sellers], March 11, 1875; 8x5; Sellers, Frederick Harrold, 1834-
    Cincinnati, A.L.S. 3p.and end. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Is taking care of their business requests.
  - Letter to G. J. Grimmer, March 11, 1875; 8x5; Sellers, George Escol
    A.L.S. 4p.,end. Draft. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Reactions to the use of his name in Gilded Age.
  - Letter to J. H. Barton, March 17, 1875; 8x5; Sellers, George Escol
    A.L.S. 8p. Draft. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Concerning the use of his name in the Gilded Age.
  - Letter to G. J. Grammer, March 17, 1875; 8x5; Sellers, George Escol
    A.L.S. 2p.,end. Draft. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Is to sue the paper for libel.
  - Letter to [Coleman] Sellers, April 22, 1875; 6x4-1/2; Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1809-1894
    Boston, A.L.S. 4p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Concerning spiritualism, education, and a microscope.
  - Letter to [Coleman] Sellers, July 25, 1875; 6x4-1/2; Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1809-1894
    A.L.S. 4p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Concerning his financial interests in steel in Pennsylvania. Concerning his microscope.
  - Letter to [Coleman] Sellers, July 30, 1875; 6x4-1/2; Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1809-1894
    Boston, A.L.S. 2p.and end. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) His interest in "turning".
  - Letter to Geo[rge] E[scol] Sellers, 1875; 10x8; Grammer, G. J.
    Evansville, Ind., A.L.S. 2p. (see Peale-Sellers Papers.) Concerning a possible libel suit.
  - Letter to F[rederick] H. Sellers, April 12, 1876; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Conley, Edward
    Cincinnati, A.L.S. 2p.and 2p.end. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Concerning the use of G.E.Sellers' name in Gilded Age.
  - Letter to Jno. A. McAllister, May 4, 1876; 9 3/4" x 7 3/4"; Peale, Titian Ramsay, 1799-1885
    Holmesburg, Draft of A.L.S. 2p. In re portrait of Gen. Washington by Charles Peale Polk presented to the Historical Society.
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Philadelphia, May 28, 1876; 10-1/2x8-1/2; Geneva. Société des arts. Classe d'industrie et de commerce.
    Geneva, L.S.: P. Cramer, Ing. 2p. In French. (see Peale-Sellers papers) Informs him that he has been made corresponding member.
  - Letter to J[ames] Burd Peale, May 31, 1876; 10x7-1/2; Hollyday, R. C.
    Annapolis Maryland, A.L.S. 3p. (see Peale papers.) Concerning C.W.Peale portraits in the State House in Annapolis.
  - Letter to [Coleman] Sellers, Oct. 20, 1876; 8x5; Sanford, Herbert B.
    A.L.S. 3p. Concerning the dispersal of the collection for the contennial exhibition.
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Nov. 23, 1876; 10-1/2x8; Centennial exhibition (1876: Philadelphia, Pa.)
    Philadelphia, A.L.S.: A.S. Gothorn. 2p. Asks him to examine certain articles and to judge them.
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Philadelphia, Feb. 24, 1877; 8x5; Kelley, William D. (William Darrah), 1814-1890
    Washington, L.S. 4p. Current events in Washington. Cannot get a bill passed which they wish.
  - Certificate of membership of the royal Norwegian Saint Olaf's Order to Coleman Sellers, May 15, 1877; 10x7-3/4; Oscar II, King of Sweden, 1829-1907
    Stockholm, D. 1p. Copy. (see Peale-Sellers papers.)
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Jr., May 18, 1877; 8x5; Steinmetz, H.
    New York, A.L.S. 4p. Is leaving for Sweden tomorrow, and has enjoyed his visit to America very much.
  - Letter to [George Escol Sellers], Jan. 30, 1878; 11x6; Sellers, Anna, 1824-1905
    Mill Bank, A.L.S. 4p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Concerning her art work. News of friends and Coleman.
  - Letter to J. H. Barton, Sept. 8, 1878; 8x5; Sellers, George Escol
    A.L.S.with initials. 5p.and end. Draft (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Concerning the use of his name in Gilded Age.
  - Letter to the Editor of the New York Sun, Sept. 9, 1878; 11-1/2x9; Sellers, George Escol
    A.L.S. 1p. Letterpress copy. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Concerning the use of his name in Gilded Age. ----Draft. 2p.
  - Letter to [George Escol Sellers], Sept. 13, 1878; 9x5-1/2; Barton, J. Hervey
    A.L.S.with initials. 2p.and add.,end. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Concerning the use of his name in Gilded Age.
  - Letter to G[eorge] E[scol] Sellers, Sept. 18, 1878; 9x5-1/2; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 3p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Family news. Concerning his having been used in Gilded Age.
  - Letter to [George Escol Sellers], Sept. 18, 1878; 9x5-1/2; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Concerning the use of his name in Gilded Age.
  - Letter to G[eorge] E[scol] Sellers, Sept. 22, 1878; 9x5-1/2; Barton, J. Hervey
    A.L.S.with initials. 3p.and end. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Concerning the use of his name in Gilded Age.
  - Letter to [Coleman Sellers], July 1, 1879; 8x5; Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1809-1894
    Boston, A.L.S. 4p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Concerning medical men he knows. Is sorry about the death in the family.
  - Letter to [Coleman] Sellers, July 2, 1879; 8x5; Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1809-1894
    Boston, A.L.S. 2p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Sends names of men for him to contact for answers to his questions.
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Philadelphia, July 26, 1879; 10x7-3/4; Folger, William Mayhew, 1844-1928
    New York, L.S. 2p. Thanks for his getting their invitation to visit Prof. Morton's institute.
  - Letter to Benson J. Lossing, Dec. 27, 1879; Peale, Titian Ramsay, 1799-1885
    Philadelphia, Photo.of A.L.S. 1p. (from original in Morristown National Historical Park.) Concerning C.W.Peale's portrait of Washington.
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, March 27, 1880; 10-1/2x8; Holloway, Joseph Flavius, 1825-1896
    Cleveland, A.L.S. 1p. Concerning a friction gear. made by the Cuyahoga steam furnace co.
  - Letter to Mrs. Lui [Peale] Grimmer, April 13, 1880; 8x5; Peale, Charles L.
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Asks genealogical date for he is collecting C.W.Peale descendents.
  - Letter to "Dear Cousin", May 13, 1880; Peale, Charles L.
    Photostat of A.L.S. 2 leaves (positive) and 4 leaves (negative-2 copies). (see Peale-Sellers papers. Peale correspondence.) Genealogy of Raphael Peale's family.
  - Letter to [Coleman] Sellers, June 26, 1880; 9x6; Dudley, Charles Benjamin, 1842-1909
    Altoona, A.L.S. 2p. (see Peale papers.) Concerning horse-power.
  - Letter to [Coleman] Sellers, Oct. 3, 1880; 8x5; Morton, Henry, 1836-1902
    This was originally located in: American Chemical Society. "The Misogynist Dinner"
    Hoboken, N.J., A.L.S. 4p. (see Peale papers.) Concerning a dispute over members for his having invited ladies to dinner. Comments on Sterry Hunt.
  - Letter to George Escol Sellers, Nov. 4, 1880; Sellers, Coleman, 1827-1907
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Jan. 1, 1881; Pepper, William, 1843-1898
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Philadelphia, Feb. 5, 1881; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Numismatic and Antiquarian Society of Philadelphia
    Philadelphia, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Henry Phillips, Jr. 1p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Has been elected a resident member.
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, April 7, 1881; 8x5; MacVeagh, Wayne, 1833-1917
    A.L.S. 1p. Concerning post for a post-master in Georgia.
  - Letter to [Coleman] Sellers, June 1, 1881; 8x5; Pepper, William, 1843-1898
    A.L.S. 1p. Will be glad to see his paper on clamps.
  - Letter to the Committee of Reception of Mechanical Engineers, Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts [Coleman Sellers, et al.], April 19, 1882; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Belgium. Commission de l'Exposition belge des beaux-arts à Philadelphie
    Philadelphia, A.L.S.: Edward Sève. 2p.and add. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Authorizes their use of galleries and notes especially painting on iron-casting in Belgium.
  - Letter to Mr. Garrett, Baltimore, April 24, 1882; 7" x 4 1/2"; Peale, Titian Ramsay, 1799-1885
    Washington, Draft of A.L.S. 2p. Wishes to sell picture representing the embarkation of the second Lord Baltimore, originally presented by Queen Anne to Annapolis, later presented to his father, Charles Willson Peale.
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Oct. 21, 1882; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    A.L.S. 1p. Returns corrected proof.
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Feb. 8, 1883; 9x5-1/2; Blodget, Lorin, 1823-1901
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. Concerning the cencus.
  - Letter to [George] Escol [Sellers], Feb. 25, 1883; 8x5; Sellers, Charles, 1806-1898
    A.L.S. 4p.,end. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Death of Mrs. Josephine Sellers. Family news.
  - Invitation to Coleman Sellers to the opening ceremonies, May 24, 1883; 6-1/2x9; New York and Brooklyn Bridge. Trustees
    Printed D.filled in in ms. 1p.and envelope. Engraving of bridge on invitation. (see Peale-Sellers papers.)
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Philadelphia, June 25, 1883; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Hermelin, Olof, 1827-1913
    A.L.S. 3p.and end. Thanks for favor.
  - Letter to [George Escol Sellers], Sept. 14, 1883; 8x5; Sellers, Anna, 1824-1905
    West Philadelphia, A.L.S. 4p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Family news.
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Philadelphia, Dec. 22, 1883; 10x8; Davenport, R. W. (Royal William), b. 1885
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. Forwards patents on hydraulics.
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Philadelphia, Jan. 8, 1884; 10x8; Westinghouse, George, 1846-1914
    Pittsburgh, Photostat of L.S. 1p. Agrees to the investment.
  - Letter to [Coleman Sellers], Jan. 16, 1884; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Dannfelt, Julie Widmark von
    Stockholm, A.L.S. 2p. Thanks for wedding present.
  - Letter to Titian R. Peale, Philadelphia, Jan. 28, 1884; 8x5; Botelet, Alexander R.
    Shepherdstown, W.Va., A.L.S. 3p.and add.envelope. (see Peale papers.) Concerning C.W.Peale and the Peale family. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Philadelphia, March 6, 1884; 11-1/4x8-1/2; Franklin Institute (Philadelphia, Pa.)
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: William H. Wahl. 1p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to [Coleman] Sellers, March 17, 1884; 8x5; Browne, John D.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p.,end. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Asks about an attempt to form a photographic society in 1862.
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, March 20, 1884; Sellers, George Escol
  - Letter to [George Escol Sellers], April 18, 1884; 8x5; Sellers, Charles, 1806-1898
    A.L.S. 3p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) News of the family. Recollections of shops in Philadelphia when he was young.
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Philadelphia, April 30, 1884; 10x8; U. S. Coast and Geodetic Survey
    Washington, A.L.S.: J.E.Hilgard. 1p. Forwards publication on standard wiregauge.
  - Letter to Professor [Coleman] Sellers, May, 1884; 15-1/2x11-1/4; University of Edinburgh
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.by the Chancellor, Rector and Principal. 1p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Asks him to convey the thanks of the University to the Franklin Institute for helping make the tercentenary a success.
  - Letter to Professor [Coleman] Sellers, May, 1884; 15-1/2x11-1/4; University of Edinburgh
    Printed L.S. by Chancellor, Rector and Principal. 1p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Presents medal for momento of the Tercentary festival of the university.
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, June 2, 1884; Sellers, George Escol
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Jr., Philadelphia, June 26, 1884; 10x6-1/2; Smith, Oberlin, 1840-1926
    Bridgeton, N.J., Typed L.S. 1p.,end. Inquires as to the date Coleman Sellers, Sr. returns from Europe.
  - Letter to Coleman [Sellers], June 30, 1884; 9x5-1/2, 2-1/2x5-1/2; Sellers, George Escol
    A.L.S. 6p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Concerning the Peale portrait of Nathan Sellers and his copy of it. Family news. Has done an article on the founding of the Franklin Institute.
  - Letter to [George] Escol [Sellers], July 23, 1884; 8x5; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
    A.L.S. 5p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Concerning their first locomotive in Pennsylvania.
    From old folder: Note: Letter is from Charles Sellers no Coleman, per Dumenic Vitiello. July 8, 2003.
  - Letter to [Coleman Sellers?], July, 1884; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Dannfelt, G.
    Helsingfors, A.L.S. 1p. Will be in Stockholm and see him.
  - Letter to Coleman [Sellers], Aug. 14, 1884; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Sellers, George Escol
    A.L.S. 4p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) History of the Sellers family.
  - Letter to Coleman [Sellers], Aug. 15, 1884; 9x5-1/2; Sellers, George Escol
    A.L.S. 6p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Concerning the Sellers' saw-mill and the building of the Penn house. Family news.
  - Letter to [Coleman] Sellers, Sept. 2, 1884; 8x5; Robinson, J. F.
    Manchester, A.L.S. Concerning the merits of a "Tandem" and a "Sociable" for riding.
  - Letter to [Coleman Sellers], Sept. 6, 1884; 8x5; Barns, A.
    A.L.S. 2P. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Concerning the meeting of the AAAS.
  - Letter to Fred[erick Harrold] Sellers, Sept. 7, 1884; 9x5-1/2; Sellers, George Escol
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Is afraid he will soon die, and wishes Fred to follow his wishes for his estate.
  - Letter to [Coleman] Sellers, Oct. 28, 1884; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Browne, John A.
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Asks if he remembers a meeting which organized a Philadelphia Society of Photographers.
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Dec. 6, 1884; 8x5; Tatham, William P., ca.1820-1899
    A.L.S. 1p. Asks a question on an engineering subject.
  - Letter to [Coleman] Sellers, Dec. 16, 1884; 8-1/2x5-1/4; Runkle, John Daniel, 1822-1902
    Brookline, Mass., A.L.S. 1p. Will forward his pamphlets as requested
  - Letter to George E[scol] Sellers, Jan. 6, 1885; 11x8; Mutual Benefit Life Insurance Company
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S: B.J.Miller, Mathematician. 1p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Concerning his policy.
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Jan. 13, 1885; 10x8; Sellers, David W. (David Wampole), 1833-1901
    Upper Darby, A.L.S. 2p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Concerning the Sellers family and the manufacture and sale of paper, moulds, wire, etc.
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Feb. 25, 1885; Sellers, George Escol
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, March 31, 1885; A.L.S. 8p.; Sellers, George Escol
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Philadelphia, July 14, 1885; 10x8; Fox, Daniel M. (Daniel Miller), b. 1809
    A.L.S. 1p. Would appreciate his dropping in.
  - Letter to Fred[erick Harrold Sellers], Aug. 31, 1885; 9x5-3/4; Sellers, George Escol
    A.L.S. 4p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Concerning his estate when he dies.
  - Letter to [Coleman] Sellers, Sept. 22, 1885; 8x5; Thaxter, Karl
    Boston, A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for his picture.
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Philadelphia, Oct. 3, 1885; 8x5; Webb, Francis William, 1836-1906
    Crewe, A.L.S. 1p.and enc.which is wanting. Forwards photograph as he promised.
  - Letter to W. H. Wahl, Oct. 22, 1885; 9x5-3/4; Ludlow, William, 1843-1901
    L.S. 1p. Thanks for publication by the Franklin institute.
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Nov. 16, 1885; Sellers, George Escol
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Dec. 14, 1885; Sellers, George Escol
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Jan. 27, 1886; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Forney, Matthias N. (Matthias Nace), 1835-1908
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. Inquires of his father.
  - Letter to [Coleman] Sellers, April 1, 1886; 7x4-1/2; Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1809-1894
    Boston, A.L.S. 1p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Thanks for his friendly letter. Forwards photographs of self.
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, May 27, 1886; Sellers, George Escol
  - Letter to [Coleman] Sellers, July 19, 1886; 8x5; Evans, W. W.
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. Concerning a commission on iron bridges.
  - Letter to A[lbert] C. Peale, Dec. 2, 1886; 8x5; Pepper, William, 1843-1898
    A.L.S. 1p.and end. (see Peale papers. Mills collection.) Congratulates him on his study of mineral waters.
  - Letter to Amza Dodd, Jan. 24, 1887; 8x5; Sellers, George Escol
    Bowlesville, Ill., A.L.S., 3p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Concerning his life-insurance policies.
  - Letter to George E[scol] Sellers, Bowlesville, Jan. 29, 1887; 11x8; Mutual Benefit Life Insurance Company
    Newark, N.J., Printed L.filled in in ms. 1p.and add. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Concerning his life-insurance policy.
  - Letter to George E[scol] Sellers, Bowlesville, Ill., Feb. 19, 1887; 10-1/2x8; Mutual Benefit Life Insurance Company
    Newark, N.J., L. 1p.,end. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Concerning his life-insurance policy.
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Philadelphia, May 5, 1887; 10-3/4x8-1/2; Tocobe, Alban E.
    Stockholm, A.L.S. 1p. Introduces Erik Bolinder.
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, May 15, 1887; A.L. 12p.; Sellers, George Escol
  - Letter to [Coleman] Sellers, June 10, 1887; 6-1/4x5; Furness, Horace Howard, 1833-1912
    Wallingford A.L.S. 4p. Concerning a publication which comes out shortly.
  - Letter to [Coleman] Sellers, June 16, 1887; 7x4-1/2; Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1809-1894
    Boston, A.L.S. 1p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Thanks for photographs. Concerning his desire for photography.
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, June 26, 1887; Dudley, Chester B.
    This was originally located in: Coleman Sellers. Mechanics, an introductory lecture.
  - Letter to [Coleman] Sellers, July 9, 1887; 7x4-1/2; Draper, Anna Palmer
    Dobbs Ferry, A.L.S. 2p. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to [Coleman] Sellers, July 12, 1887; 8x5; Furness, Horace Howard, 1833-1912
    Wallingford, A.L.S. 4p. Suggestions as to where illustrations for his work on spiritualism may be acquired. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Coleman Sellers], July 12, 1887; 8-1/2x5-1/2; White, James W.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 4p. Concerning a study of spiritualism.
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, July 15, 1887; 9-1/2x6; Koenig, George Augustus, 1844-1913
    A.L.S. 2p. Is enjoying his vacation. Will send photograph to join his collection of spiritualism exposers.
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, jr., July 27, 1887; 5-1/2x8; Trautwine, John C. (John Cresson), 1850-1924
    Philadelphia, Typed L.S. 1p.,end. Inquires for publication describing tracing teeth of cog-wheels.
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, September 8, 1887; A.L. 13p.; Sellers, George Escol
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Nov. 1, 1887; Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1809-1894
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Philadelphia, Dec. 3, 1887; 8-3/4x5-1/2; Tocobe, Alban E.
    Stockholm, A.L.S. 2p. Asks him to sell a patent in America.
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, December 15, 1887; Sellers, George Escol
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Jan. 18, 1888; Sellers, George Escol
  - Letter to [George Escol Sellers], Feb. 22, 1888; 8x5; Grimmer, Louisa Peale
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Hopes he likes Chattanooga and plans to sell her bond to raise money for him, if need be.
  - Letter to [Anna Sellers?], Feb. 23, 1888; 9-1/4x5-1/2; Sellers, George Escol
    Chattanooga, A.L.S. 4p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Describes possible sites of house in Chattanooga.
  - Letter to George Eschol [sic] Sellers, Chattanooga, March 1, 1888; 10x7-3/4; Smithsonian Institution
    Washington, A.L.S.: G. Brown Goode 4p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Concerning the development of the department of Steam Transportation.
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Sept. 19, 1888; 9-1/4x5-3/4; Metropolitan Museum of Art (New York, N.Y.)
    A.L.S.: L.P.di Clonelay(?). 1p. Invites him to be an annual member.
  - Letter to Robert B. Davidson, Philadelphia, Oct. 10, 1888; 10-1/2x8; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
    Typed L.S. 1p. Carbon copy. (see Peale papers. No.10.) Concerning a publication on the United Bowmen. His childhood memoires of the club.
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Oct. 11, 1888; 8x5; Davidson, Robert B.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 3p. (see Peale papers. No. 10.) Concerning the history of the United Bowmen and why he wrote it.
  - Letter to [Coleman] Sellers, Dec. 14, 1888; 6x5; Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1809-1894
    Boston, Printed L.with A.L.S. 2p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Friendly letter. Is sorry he has been ill.
  - Letter to [Coleman] Sellers, Dec. 19, 1888; 9-1/2x6; Hodgson, Richard, 1855-1905 (Box 19)
    Boston, A.L.S. 1P. Asks if names can be given in full in a forthcoming publication.
  - Letter to [Coleman] Sellers, March 4, 1889; 7x4-1/2; Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1809-1894 (Box 20)
    Boston, A.L.S. 1p (see Peale-Sellers papers.) His daughter is ill. Asks if he ever received a publication sent him.
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Philadelphia, March 11, 1889; 8-3/4x6; Turner, W. W.
    Cincinnati, A.L.S. 2p. Concerning a collection of pottery.